<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><resources><string-array name="places"><item>
Bancroft Library\\
general\\
Built 1949\\
Library\\
Home to many of the university Library\'s special collections, including one of the largest collections of Western Americana, the library was founded with Hubert Howe Bancroft\'s 19th century gift of his extensive library of California and Western history. The Bancroft also includes the Mark Twain Papers, the Regional Oral History Office, the University of California Archives, and other collections and artifacts. The building, designed by Arthur Brown Jr., reopened in 2009 after a major seismic upgrade; its newly renovated interior is one of the campus\'s most beautiful spaces. \\
(37.872549831536084,-122.25923359394073)	(37.871978330921266,-122.25849027118682)\\
bancroftlibrarydoeannex</item><item>
Sather Tower (Campanile)\\
general\\
Built 1914\\
Observation deck, carillon, Museum of...\\
Popularly known as the Campanile, the 307-foot tower is named for Jane K. Sather, designed by John Galen Howard, and built at a cost of $250,000. Its nickname derives from its resemblance to St. Mark\'s Campanile in Venice. The 61 bells in the carillon are played three times daily, except during exams. The four clocks, the largest in California, have 17-foot hands made of Sitka spruce and numerals of bronze. Because of the consistent temperatures on its lower floors, the Campanile also houses many of the paleontology museum\'s fossils. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982. The Campanile\'s observation deck is open daily.\\
(37.87216025143117,-122.25797295570374)	(37.87193386984895,-122.25764537534712)\\
sathertower</item><item>
Doe Memorial Library\\
general\\
Built 1917\\
Main campus library\\
Named for Charles Franklin Doe, who came from Maine in 1857 as a schoolteacher and made his fortune in California. He left a quarter of his estate to the university for construction of a new library. The Beaux Arts building, which features the magnificently restored North Reading Room and the cozy Morrison Library, was the centerpiece of architect John Galen Howard\'s classical campus ensemble. The placement of Athena, the Greek goddess of wisdom, over the main entrance reflects Berkeley\'s aspiration to become the "Athens of the West." The building was placed on the National Register of Historic Places in 1982. A four-story underground addition, the Gardner Stacks, opened in 1995 to provide more space for the library\'s holdings.\\
(37.87280390440772,-122.26015359163284)	(37.8717898905712,-122.25892478904723)\\
doelibrary</item><item>
Lower Sproul Plaza\\
life\\
Built 0\\
Favorite spot for noontime concerts,...\\
Surrounded by Zellerbach Hall, Martin Luther King, Jr. Student Union, Eshleman Hall, and C&#233;sar E. Ch&#225;vez Student Center.\\
(37.86954747075212,-122.26056665182114)	(37.868829864016774,-122.2598018713951)\\
lowersproul</item><item>
California Memorial Stadium\\
sport\\
Built 1923\\
Football, sports offices\\
Designed by John Galen Howard (although he had advised against the location, directly over the Hayward Fault and in the midst of a bird and wildlife sanctuary), the stadium opened in time for Cal to defeat Stanford there in the 1923 Big Game. It is a tribute to students killed in World War I. The stadium, sited at the mouth of Strawberry Canyon and modeled after the Coliseum in Rome, has one of the most breathtaking views in American sports.\\
(37.87219412803278,-122.25193530321121)	(37.86998169754013,-122.24938953599928)\\
memorialstadium</item><item>
Memorial Glade\\
life\\
Built 1998\\
Events, relaxation\\
Part of John Galen Howard\'s original campus design, the glade had been overwhelmed by ugly "temporary" buildings constructed during World War II. Construction of the library\'s underground Gardner Stacks and removal of the temporary structures allowed the creation of this major green open space, conducive to personal reflection and informal leisure activities. At the northwest corner of the glade is a memorial pool honoring members of the campus community who lost their lives in World War II.\\
(37.87354071078022,-122.26026892662048)	(37.87261562818835,-122.25847417793273)\\
memorialglade</item><item>
Recreational Sports Facility\\
sport, food\\
Built 1984\\
Recreational sports\\
Dozens of sporting opportunities under one roof: basketball, volleyball, handball, squash and racquetball courts, martial arts, weight and workout rooms, a fitness center, aerobics and dance classes, the Spieker Aquatics Complex. The $19.9 million facility was financed entirely with student registration fees. The Pro Shop Cafe, Open M-F 7am to 9pm and Weekends 8am to 9pm\\
(37.86895460648404,-122.26334542036057)	(37.86830898855686,-122.26226413927077)\\
rsf</item><item>
Sather Gate\\
general\\
Built 1909\\
\\
Named for pioneer California banker Peder Sather, the gate used to mark the formal south entrance to campus (until campus expanded down to Bancroft Way). It remains a popular spot for leafleting and politicking. Atop the gate are eight panels of bas-relief figures, with four nude men representing the disciplines of law, letters, medicine, and mining, and four nude women representing agriculture, architecture, art, and electricity. When the panels were first installed, public outrage led Sather to request their removal; 67 years later, the figures were rediscovered and reinstalled. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.870381707391964,-122.25972175598145)	(37.87005369764873,-122.25915009460448)\\
sathergate</item><item>
South Hall\\
general\\
Built 1873\\
School of Information\\
The oldest structure on campus, and the only surviving building of the original university nucleus, South Hall was the original home of the College of Agriculture. It once had a near twin, North Hall, situated where the Bancroft Library stands today. The brick structure, designed by Scottish architect David Farquharson, is a rare and distinguished example of the Second Empire style. Over the course of its long history, South Hall has hosted the first physics lab in America (1879), the business school, a temporary museum for the state geological survey, and the persistent myth that the rooftop scene in "Mary Poppins" was filmed there. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.8716224581179,-122.25876420736313)	(37.871044603382074,-122.25820327482222)\\
southhall</item><item>
Sproul Plaza\\
general\\
Built 0\\
Hub of campus activity and activism\\
Along with the Mario Savio Steps leading to Sproul Hall, this is the prime campus space for rallies, demonstrations, "tabling," and lunchtime speeches. Lower Sproul is a favorite spot for noontime concerts, festivals and rallies.\\
(37.870182677172906,-122.25977808237076)	(37.868838329852856,-122.25872898778914)\\
sproulhallandplaza</item><item>
Valley Life Sciences Building\\
bio, food\\
Built 1930\\
Integrative Biology, Molecular &amp;...\\
Named not for its location but for Wayne and Gladys Valley, who contributed toward the vast building\'s major renovation in the early 1990s. The largest building in Berkeley (and the largest concrete building west of the Mississippi) when it was built in 1930, it remains the biggest building on campus, at over 400,000 square feet. Original exterior decorations from the George Kelham design include animal-shaped ornaments and the names of eight life science disciplines. Inside highlights include a giant T-Rex skeleton fronting the Museum of Paleontology.\\
(37.871935818477915,-122.26312011480331)	(37.870921797429546,-122.26096058568953)\\
vlsb</item><item>
Telegraph Ave Restaurants\\
food\\
Built 0\\
Dining, Shopping\\
Numerous dining options from a wide variety of cuisines. Hours vary.\\
(37.86871322466696,-122.26008653640747)	(37.866670104465875,-122.2580021091461)\\
</item><item>
UC Berkeley Art Museum\\
art\\
Built 1970\\
Art museum\\
This major campus art center includes 11 exhibition galleries, a sculpture garden, a bookstore, and Caf&#233; Muse restaurant. It was designed by San Francisco artist Mario Ciampi and built with support from the Berkeley Centennial fund and a gift from prominent artist and professor Hans Hoffman.\\
(37.869145170518635,-122.25628584623337)	(37.86840638810868,-122.25509727678298)\\
ucbartmuseum</item><item>
Barrows Hall\\
social, gender, nature\\
Built 1964\\
Political Science, Sociology, African...\\
Named for David Prescott Barrows, political science professor and president of the university from 1919-23.\\
(37.87041135014264,-122.25853890180588)	(37.86988854412324,-122.25728595933913)\\
barrowshall</item><item>
Boalt Hall\\
law\\
Built 1966\\
School of Law\\
Originally the name of Durant Hall, which housed the law school before it moved to the southeast corner of campus. Elizabeth Joyce Boalt gave $100,000 in memory of her husband, Judge John Henry Boalt, and 40 state lawyers and judges contributed to make it the "best law school west of the Rockies."\\
(37.870479104960694,-122.25426346063614)	(37.869435428822854,-122.2523453303337)\\
boalthall</item><item>
Cory Hall\\
eng\\
Built 1950\\
Electrical Engineering &amp; Computer...\\
Named for Clarence L. Cory, dean of the College of Mechanics and a faculty member for almost 40 years, Cory had a fifth floor added in 1985, the exterior of which features a computer chip-inspired design motif. The building houses a state-of-the-art electronic micro-fabrication facility and labs devoted to integrated circuits, lasers, and robotics. Cory has the dubious distinction of being the only site bombed twice by "Unabomber" Theodore Kaczynski in the 1980s.\\
(37.875378460079524,-122.25800514221191)	(37.8747032229215,-122.25696141204833)\\
coryhall</item><item>
Dwinelle Hall\\
lang, gender, art\\
Built 1952\\
Classics, Rhetoric, Linguistics,...\\
With more than 300,000 square feet of office and classroom space, an infuriating room-numbering system, and a layout often likened to a maze, Dwinelle is the second largest building on campus. It is named for John W. Dwinelle, a UC regent, state assemblyman, and author of the 1868 "Organic Act" establishing the University of California. In the center is Ishi Court, named in honor of a Native American "found" by anthropologist Alfred Kroeber near Oroville, CA, in 1911 and brought to live in the UC Berkeley Museum of Anthropology.		Because of its site on a hill, Dwinelle has ground-level entrances on four different floors, and the same "floor" may be on two different levels a few feet apart, thanks to the building\'s dual nature as classroom and office space with their differing height requirements. The building\'s bizarre layout has spawned many tales about its origins; it has its own website (dwinelle.berkeley.edu) to help visitors sort floor from floor and fact from fiction.\\
(37.87139378890588,-122.26131230592728)	(37.87014262162047,-122.25982332906722)\\
dwinellehall</item><item>
Edwards Track Stadium / Goldman Field\\
sport\\
Built 1932\\
Track and field, soccer\\
Named for Col. George C. Edwards, one of the "Twelve Apostles" from Cal\'s first graduating class of 1873, who became a math professor the following year and remained at Berkeley for the next four decades. The 22,000-seat stadium is home field for Cal\'s soccer and track and field teams, and has witnessed dozens of world and American records, including history\'s first 15-foot pole vault. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1993.\\
(37.86980578869034,-122.26431369781494)	(37.86814576254163,-122.26553678512573)\\
edwardsstadium</item><item>
Etcheverry Hall\\
eng\\
Built 1964\\
Mechanical, Nuclear, and Industrial...\\
The first UC-built building on the north side of Hearst Ave., it was named for Bernard Etcheverry, professor of drainage and irrigation and chairman of the department for nearly three decades. It once held a functioning nuclear reactor in its basement and a research wind tunnel, both now dismantled.\\
(37.87608136589298,-122.25955009460449)	(37.87523252259794,-122.25894624671935)\\
etcheverryhall</item><item>
Evans Hall\\
compsci, eng\\
Built 1971\\
Economics, Mathematics, Statistics\\
Original home of much of the computer infrastructure on campus, the building gets poor reviews because of its dark, closed-in design, its massive scale, and its unfortunate location spoiling the main east-west axis of the campus and what was intended to be a spectacular view out to the Golden Gate. Named for Griffith Evans, math department chair from 1934-49.\\
(37.873964159383966,-122.25824117660522)	(37.87330162070864,-122.25744420967101)\\
evanshallwcampanile</item><item>
Greek Theatre\\
life\\
Built 1903\\
Outdoor Theatre\\
on the site of a natural amphitheater in the hills above campus, with funds donated by William Randolph Hearst, the Greek Theatre was the first building designed by campus architect John Galen Howard to be completed. It was modeled after the theater at Epidaurus, with a few Roman elements thrown in. The 7,200-seat open-air theater has been host to numerous commencements, concerts, plays, speeches by presidents and other luminaries, and Big Game rallies. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.874082724556864,-122.2547435760498)	(37.873250805766006,-122.25380713424681)\\
greektheaterinterior</item><item>
Haas School of Business\\
biz, food\\
Built 1995\\
Business\\
Designed by Charles Moore, the Haas School is a mini-campus of three connected buildings set around a central courtyard. Classrooms, lecture halls, and seminar rooms are wired for the 21st century, and the complex also includes a computer lab, career center, Andersen Auditorium, Cheit Hall, and a business library. The $55 million project, financed entirely through private donations, was built on the site of the former Cowell Hospital.\\
(37.87230422692625,-122.25462824106216)	(37.871256331460195,-122.25288177213667)\\
haasbusinessschool</item><item>
Haas Pavilion\\
sport\\
Built 1999\\
Basketball, gymnastics, volleyball,...\\
in 1933 as Harmon Gym; reconstructed in 1999 as Haas Pavilion, a state-of-the-art basketball arena and sports facility that preserved the intimacy, noise level, and intimidating home-court advantage of its predecessor. The 12,000-seat complex is named in honor of Walter A. Haas, Jr.\\
(37.86994976878662,-122.2627928853035)	(37.86893149596385,-122.26158822259902)\\
haaspavilion</item><item>
Hearst Memorial Mining Building\\
eng\\
Built 1907\\
Engineering, Material Sciences\\
Designed by John Galen Howard and financed by Phoebe Apperson Hearst as a memorial to her husband George, "a plain honest man and good miner," silver tycoon, and U.S. senator. The building underwent a massive restoration, completed in 2002, that included cutting-edge seismic retrofitting to protect the building in the event of a major earthquake. In addition to its meticulously restored vaulted entrance gallery, elegant sculptured windows, and grand marble staircase, the building houses new laboratories for advanced experiments in computation, ceramics, metals, and polymers, as well as facilities to develop nanoscale and superconducting materials. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.87485339352926,-122.25773692131042)	(37.87402148003853,-122.25676829299925)\\
hearstmining</item><item>
Hertz Hall\\
art\\
Built 1958\\
Music\\
Named for the 1915-30 conductor of the San Francisco Symphony, Alfred Hertz, who left his estate to Berkeley for music. Hertz Hall\'s 715-seat concert hall hosts free noontime concerts during the academic year. The building also houses the music department\'s collection of historic organs.\\
(37.87133873880444,-122.25613564252853)	(37.87080746479076,-122.25539768419264)\\
hertzhall</item><item>
International House\\
life\\
Built 1930\\
Student housing, events\\
Home to nearly 600 international and U.S. students, I-House aims to foster intercultural respect and understanding by giving students and scholars from many lands a place to live and learn together. Despite considerable community resistance to the idea of mixing different nationalities, races, and genders under one roof, it opened in the midst of Berkeley\'s fraternity and sorority row in 1930, the first coeducational student residence west of the Mississippi. The building\'s Moorish-influenced design is by George Kelham.\\
(37.87043252352002,-122.25227862596512)	(37.86916864152582,-122.25059116563796)\\
ihouse</item><item>
Kroeber Hall\\
art\\
Built 1959\\
Art Practice, Anthropology, Hearst...\\
Named for anthropology professor Alfred Kroeber, it houses the Phoebe Hearst Museum of Anthropology and the Worth Ryder Art Gallery, in addition to classroom and office space.\\
(37.87024196282494,-122.25594252347946)	(37.86933800867418,-122.25488270006178)\\
kroeberhall</item><item>
Le Conte Hall\\
phyc\\
Built 1924\\
Physics\\
This was the site of the world\'s first atom smasher, built in 1931 by Ernest O. Lawrence, Berkeley\'s first Nobel laureate. With eight Nobel Prizes in physics held by UC Berkeley faculty and four more awarded to Berkeley alumni, LeConte Hall (designed by John Galen Howard) has been home to an impressive array of Nobel-caliber work. The building was named in honor of brothers John and Joseph LeConte, professors of physics and geology who came to Berkeley in 1866 following a stint running the Confederate powder works during the Civil War. John was university president from 1877-81.\\
(37.872973285835315,-122.25770473480225)	(37.872433545622336,-122.25716794214247)\\
lecontehall</item><item>
Lewis Hall\\
phyc\\
Built 1948\\
Chemistry\\
Designed by Arthur Brown, Jr., and named for Gilbert Lewis, inventor of Lewis Dot structures and dean of the College of Chemistry from 1912-41.\\
(37.87337133065734,-122.25553214550018)	(37.8726876167453,-122.25478882274626)\\
lewishall</item><item>
McLaughlin Hall\\
eng\\
Built 1931\\
Engineering\\
Named for Donald McLaughlin, a professor at Harvard and Berkeley, first dean of engineering (1941-43), UC Regent (1951-67), and Peruvian gold mining tycoon. The building was designed by George Kelham and houses the main offices of the College of Engineering.\\
(37.87398956622367,-122.25941061973572)	(37.8736488494113,-122.25872630558013)\\
mclaughlinhall</item><item>
Martin Luther King, Jr. Student Union\\
life, food\\
Built 1961\\
Student store, Pauley Ballroom and...\\
The Student Union, owned by the ASUC Auxiliary, was constructed with funds gained from the sale of the Cal sports teams to the university in 1959. It contains an information center, multicultural center, lounges, a bookstore, restaurants and a pub, an art studio and computer lab. The building was designed by Vernon DeMars, professor of architecture.\\
(37.86945854141659,-122.26005434989929)	(37.868804455766806,-122.2592251964569)\\
mlkstudentuntion</item><item>
Moffitt Undergraduate Library\\
general, food\\
Built 1970\\
Library, Free Speech Movement Caf&#233;\\
This open-stack library for undergraduates is one of the busiest undergraduate libraries in the nation; it also houses the popular Free Speech Movement Caf&#233;. Named for James K. Moffitt, an 1886 Berkeley graduate and UC Regent from 1911-48, it was designed by John Warnecke.\\
(37.87286318795168,-122.2612452507019)	(37.87229592298107,-122.26037586412428)\\
moffitundergradlib</item><item>
Moses Hall\\
philo, social, gender\\
Built 1931\\
Philosophy and institutes for...\\
Named for Bernard Moses, history professor from 1876-1930. The George Kelham-designed building started life as Eshleman Hall, home of the Daily Cal, before it was sold to the Regents in 1959 and renamed.\\
(37.871194761421506,-122.25852817296982)	(37.870731241553564,-122.25779557905196)\\
moseshall</item><item>
North Gate Hall\\
journ\\
Built 1906\\
Graduate School of Journalism\\
This John Galen Howard building originally housed the School of Architecture and was affectionately called "the Ark." Added to the National Register if Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.87514980252571,-122.26008653640747)	(37.87467781738643,-122.25920105657576)\\
northgatehall</item><item>
Pimentel Hall\\
phyc\\
Built 1964\\
Chemistry\\
Pimentel\'s circular lecture hall is on the cutting edge of classroom technology, including a revolving stage that allows multiple professors to teach, clean up, and set up at the same time, so that the room can be used continuously despite the long setup times involved in chemistry lectures.\\
(37.87356188326835,-122.25625365972519)	(37.873261394558654,-122.25578392229079)\\
pimentalhall</item><item>
Pacific Film Archive Theater\\
art\\
Built 0\\
\\
The PFA moved from the seismically troubled Berkeley Art Museum to this Hearst Field Annex site in October 1999. It will rejoin BAM when a new museum and theater complex is built as part of a planned visual arts complex in downtown Berkeley.\\
(37.869670277752654,-122.25805073976517)	(37.868973848548755,-122.2574254342079)\\
pacificfilmarchivetheater</item><item>
Soda Hall\\
compsci\\
Built 1994\\
Computer Science\\
Funded by the Y &amp; H Soda Foundation and named in honor of Y. Charles and Helen Soda as a tribute to their commitment to education in the Bay Area. With classrooms, labs, and offices, Soda Hall was designed with its Computer Science residents in mind: its open alcoves encourage informal interactions among students and faculty, and its labs and offices are grouped to foster a team approach to computing innovation. In Soda Hall, "the building is the computer," with advanced networking, wireless capabilities, and access to computer clusters for shared computing power, storage, and services - all unique when the building opened. \\
\\
sodahall</item><item>
Sproul Hall\\
\\
Built 1941\\
Financial Aid, Registrar, Graduate...\\
Robert Gordon Sproul graduated from Berkeley in 1913, then worked his way up at his alma mater from cashier to president (1930-58). Sproul was the first Berkeley alumnus and the first native Californian to serve as university president. The neoclassical building, designed by Arthur Brown, Jr., housed the offices of the chancellor and other top administrators until the 1960s, when they were repeatedly occupied by students from the Free Speech Movement. The chancellor subsequently decamped for more-secure California Hall.\\
(37.87005563632566,-122.2592094540596)	(37.86915170327149,-122.25842321596144)\\
sproulhallandplaza</item><item>
Stanley Hall\\
bio, phyc\\
Built 2007\\
Molecular &amp; Cell Biology,...\\
Wendell M. Stanley, who won the 1946 Nobel Prize in chemistry, served Berkeley as biochemistry chair (1948-53), virology chair (1958-64), and founder and director of the virus lab (1948-69). Stanley Hall is the Berkeley headquarters for the California Institute for Quantitative Biosciences (QB3). The office and lab complex supports interdisciplinary teaching and research as part of the campus\' Health Science Initiative.\\
(37.874345261046436,-122.25664794445038)	(37.87358956472843,-122.25557739219664)\\
stanleyhall</item><item>
Sutardja Dai Hall\\
eng, food\\
Built 2009\\
Center for Information Technology...\\
This 141,000-square-foot building is the headquarters of CITRIS, the multi-campus interdisciplinary research program that is one of four California Institutes for Science and Innovation. The building houses research labs, faculty offices, a nanofabrication lab, an auditorium, and a cyber caf&#233;. CITRIS work aims to improve energy efficiency, transportation, environmental monitoring, seismic safety, education, cultural research and health care. The building honors a team of accomplished Berkeley engineering graduates: brothers Sehat and Pantas Sutardja and Weili Dai, the trio that founded Marvell Semiconductor, and Ting Chuk. Qualcomm Cybercafe open Mon-Thurs 7am-8pm and Fri 7am-4pm\\
(37.875245076592854,-122.25889563560486)	(37.87454654943753,-122.25793505392073)\\
sutardjadai</item><item>
Tang Center (University Health Services)\\
life\\
Built 1993\\
University Health Services\\
A major gift from Hong Kong businessman Jack C.C. Tang, two of whose daughters graduated from Berkeley, helped fund this center for student health care. Among the services available are acute care, radiology, a pharmacy, an optometry clinic, and various counseling services.\\
(37.86808224039017,-122.26466506719589)	(37.86730957450299,-122.26358915052413)\\
tangcenter</item><item>
Unit 1 Resident Hall\\
life\\
Built 1960\\
Student residence halls\\
to accomodate the flood of new students entering UC Berkeley in the 1960s. Designed by John Warnecke. Originally four residence halls (Cheney, Putnam, Deutsch, Freeborn), two additional residence halls (Christian and Slottman) were completed in 2005. The complex also houses the African American Theme Program (in Christian Hall) and the Disabled Students\' Residence Program (in Cheney Hall).\\
(37.868247397859506,-122.25669890642166)	(37.86728837735439,-122.25431407175063)\\
unit1</item><item>
Unit 3 Resident Hall\\
life\\
Built 1964\\
Student residence halls\\
Designed by John Warnecke, these four high-rise residence halls (Ida Sproul, Norton, Priestly, Spens-Black) were the last of the three Southside units to be built for the flood of 1960s students.\\
(37.86784509053537,-122.26144641637802)	(37.86662352639301,-122.25917959890364)\\
unit3</item><item>
Wheeler Hall\\
lang\\
Built 1917\\
English, College Writing Program,...\\
Named for Benjamin Ide Wheeler, university president during Berkeley\'s "golden years" from 1899-1919. The French Baroque facade includes arched doorways leading into a vaulted auditorium lobby, ionic columns across the middle floors, and a colonnade ornamented with urn-shaped lamps symbolizing, according to designer John Galen Howard, "the light of learning." It was added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.8716605695842,-122.25970298051834)	(37.8709853186506,-122.25860024175643)\\
wheelerhall</item><item>
Wurster Hall\\
arch, food\\
Built 1964\\
College of Environmental Design, Center...\\
Home to Berkeley\'s architecture department, and the college of environmental design. It was named for William Wurster, dean of the School of Architecture and its successor, the College of Environmental Design (1950-62), and his wife, lecturer Catherine Bauer Wurster. Ramona\'s Cafe open Mon-Thur 7am - 8pm and Fri 7am-4pm\\
(37.8711439458074,-122.2553363442421)	(37.87010451031154,-122.2541638680458)\\
wursterhall</item><item>
Zellerbach Hall\\
life\\
Built 1968\\
Cal Performances, Theater, Dance &amp;...\\
The primary fine arts performance space on campus is named for Isadore and Jennie Zellerbach, who contributed $1 million toward its construction. The 2,100-seat main auditorium has witnessed performances by many of the world\'s most acclaimed orchestras, vocalists, dance companies, and speakers. There is also a 500-seat Playhouse for smaller productions.\\
(37.869403489867544,-122.26160734891891)	(37.86877904729919,-122.26027930459975)\\
zellerbachhall</item><item>
Euclid Ave Restaurants\\
food\\
Built 0\\
Dining, Shopping\\
Numerous dining options from a wide variety of cuisines. Hours vary.\\
(37.87605595977561,-122.26089119911194)	(37.87491070622632,-122.25970799407958)\\
</item><item>
Center St. Restaurants\\
food\\
Built 0\\
Food, Shopping\\
Many different shops and restaurants. Hours Vary\\
(37.87009374860341,-122.26776838302612)	(37.870771296900685,-122.26598739624023)\\
</item><item>
Downtown Berkeley BART station\\
transit\\
Built 1973\\
Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART) Station\\
Public Transit station for traveling to San Francisco and the rest of the Bay Area\\
(37.869467010881124,-122.26794004440308)	(37.87051721701942,-122.26858377456665)\\
downtownbart</item><item>
Berkeley Dance Studio\\
art\\
Built 1898\\
Theater &amp; Dance\\
Began life as the First Unitarian Church, designed by A.C. Schweinfurth. It was acquired by the university in 1960 and added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1981.\\
(37.86883603305824,-122.26137667894363)	(37.868533433200746,-122.2609552212715)\\
berkeleydancestudio</item><item>
Old Art Gallery\\
art\\
Built 1904\\
Storage\\
Designed by John Galen Howard and originally a steam plant before being moved to its present site, the building is destined to be restored as an intimate musical performance and rehearsal space. The exterior is noted for its WPA mosaic murals depicting stret musicians and artisans.\\
(37.87076706224225,-122.25892513990402)	(37.870392470183646,-122.2584875889778)\\
oldartgallery</item><item>
Athletic Ticket Office\\
gender\\
Built 1923\\
Athletic Ticket Office, Institute of...\\
This six-story building just west of Edwards Stadium was purchased from the U.S. Farm Bureau in 1960.\\
(37.86898001505143,-122.26614564657211)	(37.86855460634707,-122.26539159498213)\\
athleticticketoffice</item><item>
Barker Hall\\
bio\\
Built 1964\\
Molecular &amp; Cell Biology, Howard...\\
Designed by William Wurster and named for Horace Albert Barker, a biochemist specializing in metabolism.\\
(37.87418011723377,-122.26580768823624)	(37.873682724027134,-122.26517701826094)\\
barkerhall</item><item>
Bechtel Engineering Center\\
eng, food\\
Built 1980\\
Engineering, Terrace Caf&#233;\\
Named for Stephen D. Bechtel, who attended Berkeley before taking the reins of the Bechtel engineering empire. It houses the Kresge Engineering Library, Sibley Auditorium, and student and interdisciplinary studies offices. Terrace Cafe on upper patio. Open M-F 8am to 3pm\\
(37.87447229449563,-122.25868105888367)	(37.873911386020616,-122.25770170173644)\\
bechtelengineeringcenter</item><item>
Birge Hall\\
phyc\\
Built 1964\\
Physics\\
Raymond Thayer Birge had been a professor of physics for 45 years (including 22 as department chair) when the new Birge Hall was named in his honor. Designed by John Warnecke, it replaced Bacon Hall (1881), formerly the university\'s elegant library and art gallery.\\
(37.87240585651992,-122.25756525993347)	(37.87198680133836,-122.25691849670409)\\
birgehalloverhead</item><item>
Botanical Garden\\
\\
Built 0\\
Botanical Garden and living museum\\
Botanical Garden at Berkeley is a living museum open to the public. The garden contains more than 12,000 different kinds of plants from all over the world on its 34 acres.\\
(37.87618722462161,-122.23982781171799)	(37.872645255763935,-122.23509336194991)\\
ucbbotanicalgarden</item><item>
Bowles Hall\\
life\\
Built 1929\\
Student housing\\
The first residence hall on campus, this medieval mansion, designed by George Kelham, has a long history of pranks, rites, and other traditions that have set "Bowlesmen" apart on an already nonconformist campus. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1989.\\
(37.873604228221524,-122.25344270467758)	(37.872984032979964,-122.25246334753035)\\
bowleshall</item><item>
Calvin Lab\\
phyc, bio\\
Built 1964\\
Chemistry, Biology, Energy Biosciences...\\
Melvin Calvin, molecular biology professor, won the 1961 Nobel Prize in Chemistry for his work on photosynthesis. He designed a round lab so that everyone\'s office would open onto a central room, thus generating creative interaction.\\
(37.87121169995171,-122.25423127412796)	(37.87081593488255,-122.2536971636772)\\
calvinlab</item><item>
Campbell Hall\\
\\
Built 1959\\
Astronomy, L&amp;S Deans\' Office,...\\
Named for William Wallace Campbell, astronomy professor, director of the Lick Observatory, and university president from 1923-30. Designed by John Warnecke. The domes on the roof contain a 10-inch reflecting telescope for undergraduate use.\\
(37.873208301921096,-122.25730508565903)	(37.87277654286198,-122.25677365741728)\\
campbellhall</item><item>
C&#233;sar E. Ch&#225;vez Student Center\\
life\\
Built 1960\\
Student advising, resources &amp;...\\
Named in honor of the charismatic founding president of the farm workers\' union. The building was once mainly a dining commons and lounge, but in 1990 it was renovated to house various student services.\\
(37.86994553408189,-122.26075440645218)	(37.86949471733034,-122.25950146398543)\\
cesarchavezcenter</item><item>
Clark Kerr Campus\\
life\\
Built 1949\\
Student housing, conference center\\
in 1949 as the California Schools for the Deaf and Blind; became the Clark Kerr Campus in 1986, named in honor of Berkeley\'s first chancellor. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.86624854400498,-122.25065588951111)	(37.86248592606088,-122.24408680877684)\\
clarkkerr</item><item>
Davis Hall\\
eng\\
Built 1968\\
Civil Engineering\\
Professor Raymond Davis spent 50 years on the Berkeley faculty and developed the Engineering Materials Laboratory into one of the world\'s finest. Davis Hall houses the offices of the Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering, including its structural and earthquake engineering labs and teaching facilities.The building\'s ground-floor \"structures bay\" rises two stories, providing space for testing many types of materials and designs, from scale models of California highway overpasses to segments of the Golden Gate Bridge.\\
(37.87472636073711,-122.25879907608032)	(37.874284017206115,-122.25780899009703)\\
davishall</item><item>
Donner Lab\\
bio\\
Built 1942\\
Molecular &amp; Cell Biology, Lawrence...\\
The lab was funded by William H. Donner, president of the Donner Steel Corp., who donated money to the university for work in nuclear medicine following his son\'s death from cancer. The Donner Lab was the world\'s first center for research in the uses of atomic energy in biology and medicine. \\
(37.87487033121834,-122.25677132606506)	(37.8742077955425,-122.25599581680297)\\
donnerlab</item><item>
Dwinelle Annex\\
art\\
Built 1920\\
Theater, Dance &amp; Performance...\\
Originally built for military science instruction, the building was designed by campus architect John Galen Howard. It was occupied for a quarter century by the music department (1933-58). In its current incarnation as home to the Department of Theater, Dance &amp; Performance Studies, it is conveniently located just steps away from Zellerbach Hall and Dwinelle Hall\'s Durham Studio Theater.\\
(37.87052145169213,-122.2616046667099)	(37.87009604365727,-122.26087743721007)\\
dwinelleannex</item><item>
Eshleman Hall\\
\\
Built 1965\\
Student Organizations\\
Owned by the Associated Students of the University of California (ASUC), Eshleman houses Berkeley\'s student government and a variety of student organizations and publications. John Eshleman was the first ASUC president, editor of the Daily Cal, state assemblyman, and lieutenant governor. The building was entirely paid for out of student fees.\\
(37.8688741459659,-122.26051837205887)	(37.86860118963075,-122.2599091597557)\\
eshlemanhall</item><item>
Evans Diamond\\
sport\\
Built 1933\\
Baseball\\
Evans Diamond, home of the Cal baseball team since 1933, honors legendary coach Clint Evans, who served as the Bears\' head coach from 1930-54. The picturesque field features natural grass and seating for 2,500.\\
(37.87017420779033,-122.26429492235184)	(37.868914555692434,-122.26248944482802)\\
evansdiamond</item><item>
Faculty Club\\
\\
Built 1903\\
Dining club, guest rooms, events\\
Designed by distinguished local architect Bernard Maybeck, this rustic Arts and Crafts structure provides dining facilities for faculty members and guests, and temporary residential quarters for visiting professors, members and their guests. It was added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.87213484396042,-122.25644141435623)	(37.871480767585915,-122.25533331117629)\\
facultyclub</item><item>
Foothill Residence Halls\\
life\\
Built 1990\\
Student housing\\
Foothill\'s wood-shingled buildings, surrounded by tall trees, provide views of the Bay and the city of Berkeley from a quiet Northside neighborhood.\\
(37.87656831478278,-122.2569751739502)	(37.875537395755195,-122.25567395172118)\\
foothilllaloma</item><item>
Genetics and Plant Biology Building\\
bio, food\\
Built 1990\\
Molecular &amp; Cell Biology, Plant...\\
One of four circa-1990 building projects aimed at revitalizing the biological sciences on the Berkeley campus, this building houses classrooms, laboratories, and office space. Pat Brown\'s Cafe open M-F 7:30am - 3:30pm\\
(37.87359999373033,-122.2650620341301)	(37.873238104380604,-122.26446355066298)\\
gpb</item><item>
Giannini Hall\\
nature\\
Built 1930\\
Natural Resources (Agricultural &amp;...\\
Designed by William C. Hays, this building was named for benefactor Amadeo Peter Giannini, founder of the Bank of Italy (which eventually became the Bank of America). The light-splashed entry hall and grand split staircase are filled with Art Deco details. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.873930283584315,-122.26284116506577)	(37.87306872176847,-122.2618564435005)\\
gianninihall</item><item>
Gilman Hall\\
phyc\\
Built 1917\\
Chemistry, Chemical Engineering\\
Daniel Coit Gilman was a geology professor at Yale who became the University of California\'s second president (1872-75) before going on to found the Johns Hopkins University. The building was designed by John Galen Howard. Room 307, where plutonium was discovered in 1941, was added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1966.\\
(37.87288859517018,-122.25655138492584)	(37.87232768158061,-122.25606018981932)\\
gilmanhall</item><item>
Goldman School\\
public\\
Built 1928\\
Public Policy\\
This Tudor-style mansion began life as the Beta Theta fraternity chapter house, and was one of the first buildings in the heavily wooded residential neighborhood on the north border of campus. Among early chapter members were noted architects Charles Keeler (inspiration for Berkeley\'s famous Hillside Club), John Baker Jr. and Arthur Brown Jr., who singly or together designed Berkeley\'s City Hall, San Francisco\'s City Hall and Opera House, and two future expansions for the fraternity chapter house. (Brown also served as the University of California\'s supervising architect.)		The main 1893 structure was designed by English-trained Ernest Coxhead. According to an 1894 issue of the Berkeley Weekly Herald, it contained "eight bedrooms, kitchen, dining room, reception room, library and a large chapter hall, which can be used for dancing."		After a number of additions to the building in the first third of the 20th century, the Betas moved out in 1966 when the property was purchased by the university. The new School of Public Policy moved in in 1969, and in 1997 was named in honor of Richard and Rhoda Goldman, generous Berkeley alumni. An annex fronting LeRoy Ave. was completed in 2002.\\
(37.87600514751355,-122.25837260484695)	(37.875414600877505,-122.25766146860121)\\
goldmanschool</item><item>
Hargrove Music Library\\
art\\
Built 2004\\
Music\\
Home of the No. 1 academic library in the United States, this high-tech building in the "arts quadrangle" houses 190,000 volumes of printed music, books, and periodicals; more than 50,000 recordings; manuscripts; and other rare materials.\\
(37.87062308374215,-122.25643068552017)	(37.87024849187115,-122.255821473217)\\
hargrovemusic</item><item>
Haviland Hall\\
social\\
Built 1924\\
Social Welfare, Public Health\\
Designed by John Galen Howard and named in honor of San Francisco banker J.T.H. Haviland, whose wife donated the funds for the building. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.873995917931495,-122.26132303476334)	(37.87346041396578,-122.26077819547652)\\
havilandhall</item><item>
Hearst Memorial Gym\\
sport\\
Built 1927\\
Physical Education, ROTC\\
Campus architect John Galen Howard was away in Europe when the UC Regents awarded the design of the gymnasium to celebrated local architects Bernard Maybeck and Julia Morgan. It was named for campus benefactor and UC Regent Phoebe Apperson Hearst and added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982. In addition to large and small gymnasiums and outdoor swimming pools, the building once contained an indoor rifle range. \\
(37.87007680981523,-122.25768059492111)	(37.869134764980366,-122.25610042295455)\\
hearstgym</item><item>
Hellman Tennis Center\\
sport\\
Built 0\\
Tennis courts\\
If you love tennis, you\'ll love these courts.\\
(37.87027160563457,-122.2657299041748)	(37.869702217443816,-122.26427847824095)\\
hellmantennis</item><item>
Hildebrand Hall\\
phyc\\
Built 1966\\
Chemistry, QB3\\
Named after Joel Hildebrand, longtime chemistry professor and dean, and the inventor of Chem-1A\'s fabled Big Game Titration. The building houses graduate research laboratories, undergraduate teaching labs, and the chemistry library.\\
(37.87283778072516,-122.25599884986877)	(37.87230650926753,-122.25533062896727)\\
hildebrandhall</item><item>
Hilgard Hall\\
nature\\
Built 1917\\
Environmental Science, Policy &amp;...\\
Designed by John Galen Howard, this was one of the first campus buildings to acknowledge the city of Berkeley (by attempting to face both inward and outward at the same time). It was named for Eugene Hilgard, an agriculture professor who founded the University Agricultural Experimental Station. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.873777842297244,-122.26369947195053)	(37.87287816916945,-122.26306343755721)\\
hilgardhall</item><item>
Latimer Hall\\
phyc\\
Built 1963\\
Chemistry\\
Named for Wendell Latimer, dean of the College of Chemistry in the 1940s, the building contains chemistry labs and classrooms. On the plaza southwest of Latimer Hall is a cupola, all that remains of the original chemistry building on campus.\\
(37.873337454585965,-122.25634753704071)	(37.87291416519173,-122.25552374801634)\\
latimerhall</item><item>
Life Sciences Addition\\
bio\\
Built 1988\\
Molecular &amp; Cell Biology\\
Part of a major campus drive to improve facilities for biology studies, the six-story LSA houses 46 laboratory suites for advanced biological research.\\
(37.87188076878143,-122.26361900568008)	(37.870917562849655,-122.26278448781966)\\
lsa</item><item>
Maxwell Family Field\\
sport\\
Built 1955\\
Field hockey, Lacrosse\\
Formerly known as Kleeberger Fields, Maxwell Family Field is located east of the main campus, on Gayley Road, just north of Memorial Stadium. It's artificial turf is a multi-use playing field. Evening field lights are available.\\
(37.87293517504792,-122.25366801023483)	(37.87178142022331,-122.25200200757979)\\
maxwellfield</item><item>
McCone Hall\\
social, nature\\
Built 1961\\
Earth &amp; Planetary Science, Geography\\
Designed by John Warnecke, McCone Hall houses several academic departments in the earth sciences, as well as the Berkeley Seismological Laboratory, one of the world\'s foremost centers for the study of earthquakes, and the Earth Sciences and Map Library. It is named for alumnus and former CIA director John McCone.\\
(37.87448923227232,-122.26003289222717)	(37.87367425336905,-122.25921446762084)\\
mcconehall</item><item>
Morrison Hall\\
art\\
Built 1958\\
Music\\
May T. Morrison, class of 1878, left money for this building in her will, as well as for the Morrison Library in Doe.\\
(37.87120323068709,-122.25698858499527)	(37.870714289715714,-122.25603604993819)\\
morrisonhall</item><item>
Mulford Hall\\
nature\\
Built 1948\\
Natural Resources, Environmental...\\
Named for Water Mulford, first dean of the School of Forestry, 1914-47. Much of the interior is wood-paneled or covered by planks from native California trees (most donated by lumber companies) or foreign species (most obtained from the 1915 Panama Pacific Exposition).\\
(37.87285048433808,-122.26499766111374)	(37.87243778072333,-122.26399148187636)\\
mulfordhall</item><item>
O\'Brien Hall\\
eng\\
Built 1959\\
Engineering\\
Morrough O\'Brien spent two decades as an engineering professor before serving as dean of the College of Engineering from 1948-59. O\'Brien Hall houses environmental engineering and the Water Resources Center Archives.\\
(37.87468401642439,-122.259281873703)	(37.87411463943588,-122.25881750068663)\\
obrienhall</item><item>
C. V. Starr East Asian Library\\
general\\
Built 2008\\
\\
Berkeley�s vast collection of East Asian manuscripts and artifacts -- assembled over the past century -- is housed in this library, the first freestanding structure at a U.S. university erected solely for East Asian collections. The library is home to more than 900,000 volumes, primarily in Chinese, Japanese, and Korean, plus thousands of manuscripts, rubbings, and the largest and most valuable collection of historic Japanese maps outside of Japan. It is also the largest U.S. academic repository of materials on the People\'s Republic of China. It is named for the late Cornelius Vander Starr, an insurance pioneer with a deep interest in Asia and a major donor to the building fund for the library.\\
(37.873741849170585,-122.26073563098907)	(37.873356670274745,-122.2599467106819)\\
eastasianlibrary</item><item>
Stephens Hall\\
gender\\
Built 1923\\
International &amp; Area Studies,...\\
The building, which formerly served as the Student Union, was designed in Collegiate Gothic style by John Galen Howard and named for Henry Morse Stephens, a professor and student adviser.\\
(37.871681742612566,-122.25792735815048)	(37.87100225686117,-122.25724304399489)\\
stephenshall</item><item>
Stern Hall\\
life\\
Built 1942\\
Student housing\\
This all-female dorm is named for Rosalie Stern, whose husband, Sigmund, served as manager of the Blue and Gold yearbook. It was the first university-owned residence hall for women.\\
(37.875310709767206,-122.2559130191803)	(37.87425860628423,-122.25445086441039)\\
sternhall</item><item>
Tan Hall\\
phyc\\
Built 1996\\
Chemistry, Chemical Engineering\\
Named in honor of Tan Kah Kee, a pioneering industrialist and philanthropist in China and Singapore.\\
(37.87335227536912,-122.25670963525772)	(37.872886640415295,-122.25619161806105)\\
tanhall</item><item>
Tolman Hall\\
social\\
Built 1962\\
Education, Psychology, Institute for...\\
Tolman Hall\'s mid-20th century modernist look, inspired by the work of famed architect Le Corbusier, won a major award for architect Gardner Dailey, who also designed Evans, Morrison, Hertz, and Kroeber Halls. Less-impressed reports that its labyrinthine design and inscrutable room-numbering system were inspired by the rat-maze experiments of its namesake, behavioral psychologist Edward Chace Tolman, are the stuff of urgan legend. Today, the building is sorely overcrowded and its signature suspended breezeway and molded concrete decorations are slated for a seismic overhaul.\\
(37.87449770115827,-122.2647026181221)	(37.87370812981339,-122.26315463266371)\\
tolmanhall</item><item>
University House\\
\\
Built 1907\\
Chancellor\'s residence\\
French architect Henri Jean Emile Benard was the winner of the university\'s Comprehensive Building Plan of 1900, funded by campus benefactor Phoebe Apperson Hearst. Benard collected his $10,000 prize, but declined appointment as the campus\'s supervising architect (balking at leaving the sophistication of Paris for Berkeley\'s turn-of-the-century ruggedness); University House is the only building from his plan that was actually constructed. Surrounding the stately home are extensive gardens and a large floral clock donated by the Swiss government. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.87464167208638,-122.26247638463974)	(37.87431365783582,-122.26205492696761)\\
universityhouse</item><item>
Underhill Parking Facility &amp; Playing Field\\
sport\\
Built 2008\\
\\
Atop the lot, a 77,400-square-foot, synthetic-turf playing field hosts intramural sports leagues, sports-club practices, and special events.\\
(37.867325263866874,-122.25567564368248)	(37.866544123822386,-122.25417057356833)\\
underhillparking</item><item>
Unit 2 Resident Hall\\
life\\
Built 1960\\
Student residence halls\\
Designed by John Warnecke, and built to accommodate the surge of new students in the 1960s. The original four high-rise residence halls (Davidson, Griffiths, Ehrman, Cunningham) were joined by two new halls, Towle and Wada, in 2005.\\
(37.86660004130004,-122.25568503141403)	(37.86545469209692,-122.25383663854598)\\
unit2</item><item>
University Hall\\
public\\
Built 1959\\
Public Health, Environmental Health...\\
This seven-story tower at the west edge of campus, designed by Welton Becket &amp; Associates, originally housed the University of California Office of the President. When UCOP relocated to Oakland, University Hall became home to a variety of administrative offices.\\
(37.872364569513806,-122.2666834294796)	(37.87147335557528,-122.26603666625022)\\
universityhall</item><item>
Wickson Natural Area\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
This peaceful preserve, marked by wooden bridges crossing a meandering fork of Strawberry Creek, was dedicated in 1969 in honor of Edward Wickson, dean of the College of Agriculture from 1906-1912. It includes some of the oldest trees on campus, including a stand of coast redwoods dating from the 1870s, and a magnificent Chinese gingko planted in 1881.\\
(37.87400756272743,-122.26213440299034)	(37.87344665176585,-122.26154128394126)\\
wicksonnatural</item><item>
Koshland Hall\\
bio\\
Built 1990\\
Plant &amp; Microbial Biology,...\\
Named for Daniel Koshland, a Berkeley alumnus, biochemistry professor, and longtime editor of Science magazine.\\
(37.87415894492439,-122.2651720046997)	(37.87371855949026,-122.26463556289673)\\
koshlandhall</item><item>
UC Press Building\\
\\
Built 0\\
UC Press\\
This WPA-financed project is a fine example of New Deal Moderne style. The severe façade features shallow-relief piers and fluted spandrels, while the lobby with its spiral stair, polished terrazzo floor, and colorful stained glass gives full expression to Moderne exuberance. The United Nations Charter was printed here in 1945. The building is slated for demolition when U.C. builds its proposed downtown hotel, conference cente and museum complex.\\
(37.87286318795155,-122.26704955101013)	(37.873142666873456,-122.26756453514099)\\
ucpressbuilding</item><item>
Architectural Research Facility\\
social\\
Built 1910\\
Anthropology, Archaeology\\
The Archaeological Research Facility once housed Zeta Psi, the oldest fraternity west of the Misissippi River.\\
(37.87033089121622,-122.25402474403381)	(37.8700388736952,-122.2536435194969)\\
archresearchfacility</item><item>
Center for Latin American Studies\\
lang, gender\\
Built 1920\\
Center for Latin American Studies\\
The Center for Latin American Studies (CLAS) at UC Berkeley is a National Resource Center dedicated to promoting research and community awareness about issues affecting Latin America.\\
(37.86749783402697,-122.2569751739502)	(37.86721217538813,-122.25657517395018)\\
</item><item>
Institute for Research on Labor and Employment\\
biz\\
Built 1928\\
Institute for Research on Labor and...\\
The Institute for Research on Labor and Employment (IRLE) is an "Organized Research Unit" of the University of California at Berkeley. IRLE was founded in 1945. Its first director was UC President Emeritus Clark Kerr. The current Director is Michael Reich. IRLE brings together faculty from several academic departments and supports multidisciplinary research about labor and employment relations.\\
(37.86728820887613,-122.25806146860123)	(37.86704913436861,-122.25768829069136)\\
</item><item>
Alumni House\\
\\
Built 1954\\
Alumni Association\\
with funds from thousands of alumni donations, this contemporary structure along the banks of Strawberry Creek is a meeting place for alumni revisiting campus and headquarters for the California Alumni Assocation.\\
(37.86996247289936,-122.26169317960739)	(37.8694904825075,-122.26085866174697)\\
alumnihouse</item><item>
A&amp;E\\
\\
Built 1929\\
Capital Projects\\
Building for Architects &amp; Engineers. Was designed by W.P. Stephenson. Now houses the campus planning staff.\\
(37.8702313761061,-122.25895196199417)	(37.8700833410041,-122.25859755954741)\\
</item><item>
Anthony Hall\\
\\
Built 1957\\
Graduate Assembly\\
Named for alumnus Earle C. Anthony, the world\'s most prominent Packard car dealer, who founded (in 1903) the Pelican, Berkeley\'s first humor magazine, during his student years.\\
(37.87080940880639,-122.25846916437149)	(37.870549153054036,-122.25797796926497)\\
anthonyhall</item><item>
Bancroft Parking Structure\\
\\
Built 0\\
Parking\\
A number of wonderful spots to park your car. We think you\'ll really like this one.\\
(37.869966707604924,-122.25624561309814)	(37.8692025202155,-122.25534135780333)\\
bancroftparkingstructure</item><item>
Banway Building\\
\\
Built 1961\\
Career Center, Information Systems...\\
Students can find employment and internship opportunities through the services of the Career Center.\\
(37.86797848742482,-122.26757526397705)	(37.86763142310085,-122.26705724678038)\\
banwaybuilding</item><item>
Blum Hall\\
eng\\
Built 2010\\
Blum Center for Developing Economies,...\\
A campus hub for anti-poverty innovation, the center\'s home is a new 22,000-square-foot complex comprised of the renovated Naval Architecture Building (built in 1914), a new three-story wing and terraces, bridges and plazas connecting the complex to the College of Engineering\'s Sutardja Dai Hall. The center\'s Global Poverty and Practice program is the campus\'s fastest growing minor, with nearly 500 students currently declaring it their secondary field of study.		Named for Richard C. Blum, the center supports faculty research aimed at creating lasting change for the poor around the world.		The original Naval Architecture Building was designed by John Galen Howard and placed on the National Register of Historic Places in 1976.\\
(37.87512439608716,-122.25934088230133)	(37.874739216591266,-122.25849027118682)\\
blumhall</item><item>
California Hall\\
\\
Built 1905\\
Chancellor\'s office, university...\\
The building began life as the campus administration building, a role to which it has somewhat returned after decades of classroom use. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.87218565889106,-122.26068466901779)	(37.87154005173477,-122.25998962602614)\\
californiahallwest</item><item>
Chancellor\'s Esplanade\\
life\\
Built 0\\
Chancellor\'s residence\\
This green expanse between Tolman Hall and the chancellor\'s residence at University House, shaded by towering Italian stone pine trees, is a popular spot for ceremonies or relaxing between classes.\\
(37.87465014095666,-122.26188898086548)	(37.87425014095666,-122.26148898086548)\\
universityhouse</item><item>
Class of 1914 Fountain\\
\\
Built 1964\\
\\
The monument is a gift of the class of 1914.\\
(37.869532649203336,-122.25473552942276)	(37.86942042881056,-122.25455313920975)\\
class1914fountain</item><item>
Cleary Hall\\
life\\
Built 1992\\
Student housing\\
Across the street from the Unit 3 high-rise residence halls, Cleary Hall is home to two of the campus\'s residence hall theme programs: Casa Magdalena Mora for Chicano/Latino studies, and the Asian Pacific American theme program. It is named for prize-winning children\'s book author (and Cal alum) Beverly Cleary.\\
(37.866845664928135,-122.2594803571701)	(37.86633324230276,-122.26028501987457)\\
clearyhall</item><item>
Springer Gateway / Crescent\\
\\
Built 1964\\
\\
This plaza and stairway was a gift of Russell Severance Springer, a Cal alum from the class of 1902. Thousands of pedestrians stream through the west entrance of campus each day from downtown Berkeley and the nearby BART station.\\
(37.87194005306974,-122.26553946733475)	(37.871540053069744,-122.26513946733475)\\
springergateway</item><item>
Durant Hall\\
\\
Built 1911\\
East Asian Languages &amp; Cultures\\
Originally the Boalt Memorial Hall of Law, it was renamed for Henry Durant, the university\'s first president in 1870-72, after the law school moved to the southeast side of campus in 1951. Designed by John Galen Howard. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.87147001205542,-122.26045936346054)	(37.8710234309983,-122.25977504930495)\\
duranthall</item><item>
Ellsworth Parking Structure\\
\\
Built 0\\
Parking\\
Quite possibly named after S. George Ellsworth who edited the journals of Addison Pratt, the autobiography of Louisa Barnes Pratt and \"Dear Ellen: Two Mormon Women and Their Letters\". Ellsworth\'s wife was descended from Addison and Louisa Barnes Pratt.\\
(37.865621773575725,-122.26173877716064)	(37.86630783282368,-122.26317644119263)\\
ellsworthparking</item><item>
Eucalyptus Grove/Grinnell Natural Area\\
life\\
Built 0\\
Park Area\\
This grove, planted more than a century ago on the north bank of Strawberry Creek, began life as a windbreak for a running track located where the Life Sciences Addition now stands. The blue gum eucalyptus, some reaching nearly 200 feet high, are thought to be the tallest stand of hardwood trees in North America. Across Strawberry Creek to the south lies the Grinnell Natural Area, where stands of redwood, Monterey pine and coast live oak give an idea of what this land looked like before the arrival of campus. It is named for the first director of the Museum of Vertebrate Zoology, professor Joseph Grinnell.\\
(37.871995102721954,-122.26486891508102)	(37.8706804223796,-122.26316536149977)\\
eucalyptusgrove</item><item>
Faculty Glade\\
life\\
Built 0\\
Open grassy area\\
This natural amphiteater is one of the most popular spaces on campus for picknicking and outdoor study. It may once have been the site of an Ohlone Native American settlement that harvested fresh water and fish from adjoining Strawberry Creek.\\
(37.871736792457725,-122.25707441568375)	(37.871078479886975,-122.2560736008644)\\
facultyglade</item><item>
Founders\' Rock\\
\\
Built 0\\
Campus Monument\\
A monument at the southwest corner of Hearst Ave. and Gayley Rd. marks the spot where trustees of the College of California gathered on April 16, 1860, to dedicate a new campus for higher learning. Eight years later the institution merged with the new state-chartered Agricultural, Mining and Mechanical Arts College to form the University of California; the first classes were held on the Berkeley campus in 1873.\\
(37.87548008543115,-122.25714683532715)	(37.875156304950686,-122.25673610649108)\\
foundersrock</item><item>
Giauque Hall\\
phyc\\
Built 1954\\
Chemistry\\
Chemist William F. Giauque won the Nobel Prize in 1949 for low-temperature research. Labs in the largely underground building conduct research into properties of matter at supercold temperatures.\\
(37.872803904408485,-122.25629925727844)	(37.8722980402437,-122.2557329603195)\\
giauquehall</item><item>
Girton Hall\\
\\
Built 1912\\
Child care\\
Designed by Julia Morgan as Senior Women\'s Hall, it was paid for entirely by university women and named for Girton College, Cambridge\: the first women\'s college at a university in England. Added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1991.\\
(37.87251595508597,-122.25436002016068)	(37.87223028865996,-122.25396002016066)\\
girtonhall</item><item>
Hearst Field Annex\\
phyc\\
Built 1999\\
Physics Astronomy Library, Physics, CS\\
This complex of metal-frame buildings hosts a changing array of departments and service units displaced by construction or space shortages elsewhere on campus.\\
(37.869848135806016,-122.25846379995346)	(37.86909241733878,-122.25756490907668)\\
hearstfieldannex</item><item>
Hearst Mining Circle\\
life, eng\\
Built 1914\\
Open grassy area\\
Directly south of Hearst Memorial Mining Building, the circle is a tranquil oasis at the east entrance to campus, surrounded by green and featuring a beautiful circular reflecting pool at its center. Obscured during several years of construction in the area, as the mining building was renovated and Stanley Hall was built, the well-loved Berkeley gathering spot is being restored to its original prominence, a priority of the campus\'s Landscape Master Plan.\\
(37.87390911120349,-122.2573909163475)	(37.87339901427004,-122.25662613592146)\\
miningcircle</item><item>
Hesse Hall\\
eng\\
Built 1924\\
Mechanical Engineering\\
Designed by John Galen Howard and named for the Prussian-born founder of the College of Mechanics, Frederick Godfrey Hesse.\\
(37.874582389974485,-122.2596788406372)	(37.87409770198692,-122.25903207740782)\\
hessehall</item><item>
Ida Louise Jackson Graduate House\\
\\
Built 2002\\
Graduate student housing\\
The first building at UC Berkeley named for an African-American woman \: Ida Louise Jackson, daughter of a slave and pioneering educator in both California and her native Deep South.\\
(37.8678747343128,-122.25375652313232)	(37.86829821548225,-122.25437879562378)\\
idalouise</item><item>
Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory\\
\\
Built 1931\\
Scientific research\\
Founded in 1931 by Ernest Orlando Lawrence as the Berkeley Radiation Laboratory, this U.S. Department of Energy facility is managed by the University of California. Among the 76 buildings nestled in the hills above the UC Berkeley campus is the Advanced Light Source, formerly Lawrence\'s 184-inch cyclotron, which played a key role in opening the Atomic Age. \\
(37.87838481745622,-122.25258708000183)	(37.876765345449705,-122.2494834133148)\\
berkeleylab</item><item>
Lawrence Hall of Science\\
\\
Built 1968\\
\\
Established at the University of California at Berkeley in honor of Ernest O. Lawrence, UC\'s first Nobel laureate, Lawrence Hall of Science is a resource center for preschool through high school science and mathematics education, and a public science center with hands-on experiences for learners of all ages.\\
(37.879807501554325,-122.24780201911926)	(37.87842517021157,-122.24564249000548)\\
lawrencehallofscience</item><item>
Lower Hearst Parking Structure\\
\\
Built 0\\
\\
Often thought of as the weaker little brother to Upper Hearst Parking Structure. Don\'t let names fool you though, Lower Hearst has got some pretty nice parking spots.\\
(37.87551396051792,-122.26223230361938)	(37.87491070898613,-122.26055557212828)\\
lowerhearstparking</item><item>
Ludwig\'s Fountain\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
Named in 1961 by Regental decree; honors a German short-haired pointer named Ludwig von Schwarenberg, who loved to wade in it, awaiting a friendly student to throw a tennis ball or a snack.\\
(37.86970415551137,-122.25970298051834)	(37.869393085033636,-122.25930298051833)\\
ludwigsfountain</item><item>
Manville Hall\\
life\\
Built 1995\\
Student Housing\\
\\
(37.86587163539935,-122.26754039525986)	(37.865344586430695,-122.26644302091597)\\
manville</item><item>
Minor Hall\\
\\
Built 1941\\
Optometry\\
Named for Ralph S. Minor, whose 1903-46 tenure as an optometry professor included a stint as dean of the School of Optometry. Designed by Arthur Brown, Jr. Although the building began life housing mathematics, journalism, and "defense" courses, it was given over to the Radiation Laboratory during the wartime development of the atomic bomb. It was remodeled in 1953 for the exclusive use of the School of Optometry.\\
(37.87180031145875,-122.25486427545547)	(37.87115893765308,-122.25458229265212)\\
minorhall</item><item>
Morgan Hall\\
bio\\
Built 1953\\
Nutritional Sciences &amp; Toxicology\\
Named for Agnes Fay Morgan, professor of nutrition from 1915-54.\\
(37.87362540069474,-122.26443439722061)	(37.872950156619034,-122.26391101560591)\\
morganhall</item><item>
Natural Resources Laboratory\\
\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.874988894932784,-122.26654529571533)	(37.87456545221925,-122.26696372032166)\\
</item><item>
North Field\\
\\
Built 0\\
\\
It\'s a field, no doubt about that. But, is it really in the north?\\
(37.87050874767493,-122.25745797157288)	(37.87002599343102,-122.25628852844238)\\
</item><item>
North Gate\\
\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.87481104929152,-122.26026356220245)	(37.874639709138386,-122.25993329963683)\\
northgate</item><item>
Observatory Hill\\
\\
Built 0\\
\\
This rise just west of McCone Hall was the site of the Students\' Observatory, built in 1885 to house a variety of astronomical instruments, including a 20" telescope. Two years later, the observatory added the first seismographic equipment deployed by the University of California, and in 1891 a glass conservatory was built on the hill as part of the original campus botanical garden. The conservatory was razed in 1924; the observatory moved to Lafayette in 1965. The site is now an open space for relaxing or studying, bordered on its south flank by the new C.V. Starr East Asian Library and Chang-Lin Tien Center for East Asian Studies.\\
(37.87468825085701,-122.2611352801323)	(37.87378011447589,-122.26016665182112)\\
observatoryhill</item><item>
Oxford Research Unit\\
\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.87513286490118,-122.26751357316971)	(37.874694755231104,-122.26697946271895)\\
ucgreenhouse</item><item>
Public Affairs\\
\\
Built 1974\\
Public Affairs\\
A bike shop and a bank in former lives; now home to the Berkeleyan newspaper, web NewsCenter, Media Relations, and other communications operations.\\
(37.867273386870345,-122.26539731025696)	(37.867578296046055,-122.26579427719116)\\
publicaffairs</item><item>
Residential &amp; Student Services Building\\
\\
Built 2003\\
Residential &amp; Student Services,...\\
\\
(37.86711246207647,-122.2563636302948)	(37.866488012529594,-122.25566322288512)\\
rssbuilding</item><item>
Senior Hall\\
\\
Built 1906\\
Order of the Golden Bear\\
This log cabin behind the Faculty Club was originally a meeting hall for the senior class. It was the first campus building to be built with student donations. Spared from planned dismantling in 1973, it was added to the National Register of Historic Places the following year. It is the meeting place for the Order of the Golden Bear.\\
(37.87220365583726,-122.25597605109215)	(37.871820594227515,-122.25516835532187)\\
seniorhall</item><item>
Simon Hall\\
law\\
Built 1966\\
Law school\\
Once a residence hall for law students, it now houses offices for faculty, student organizations, and student publications.\\
(37.87020490929733,-122.25310072302818)	(37.86961011330257,-122.25241104445456)\\
manvillehall</item><item>
Spieker Plaza\\
\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86903506691435,-122.26253539323807)	(37.868372510352195,-122.26156140050887)\\
spiekerplaza</item><item>
University Hall Parking Structure\\
\\
Built 0\\
\\
This parking structure is a prototype of a possible parking structure suitable for the surface of the Moon.\\
(37.87133873880737,-122.2670066356659)	(37.87089639254744,-122.26612920246123)\\
universityhall</item><item>
Upper Hearst Parking Structure\\
\\
Built 0\\
Parking\\
An amazing parking lot, it even has a Tennis court on top\\
(37.875979741370415,-122.25773692131042)	(37.875478116294225,-122.25685412368773)\\
upperhearstparking</item><item>
Earl Warren Hall\\
\\
Built 2005\\
IST, administration\\
This high-tech building is home to several units of the campus�s Information Services and Technology unit, a central facility for campus IT and computing. The building provides a stable and secure home for much of the campus\'s data infrastructure. It was named in 2008 for the late Chief Justice of the U.S. Supreme Court Earl Warren -- a Berkeley graduate and former California governor -- after the demolition of the original Warren Hall, which was located on a nearby site.\\
(37.87459085884978,-122.26739555597305)	(37.87421626561043,-122.26645911417006)\\
earlwarrenhall</item><item>
Wellman Hall\\
nature\\
Built 1912\\
Environmental Science, Policy &amp;...\\
Harry Wellman, professor of agricultural economics, was acting university president in 1967 when the building\'s name was changed from Agriculture Hall. Designed by John Galen Howard and added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1982.\\
(37.873333220074954,-122.26315766572952)	(37.872865468088555,-122.2623767920494)\\
wellmanhall</item><item>
West Circle\\
\\
Built 0\\
\\
A Circle in the West...\\
(37.87234763124861,-122.26388320326805)	(37.87194763124861,-122.26348320326805)\\
westcircle</item><item>
West Gate\\
\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.87196651925229,-122.2652779519558)	(37.87156651925229,-122.2648779519558)\\
westgate</item><item>
Women\'s Faculty Club\\
\\
Built 1923\\
Dining club, guest rooms, events\\
The wood-framed structure designed by John Galen Howard includes living rooms, a lounge, and dining rooms.\\
(37.87219836261824,-122.25520759820938)	(37.871878819943035,-122.25461984357833)\\
womenfacultyclub</item><item>
Delta Kappa Epsilon Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86945007194977,-122.25286602973938)	(37.86920252324924,-122.25235874137877)\\
</item><item>
Pi Kappa Alpha Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.869026597400406,-122.25290894508362)	(37.86870282364264,-122.25231582603453)\\
</item><item>
Delta Delta Delta Sorority\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86923833497933,-122.25152492523193)	(37.86890609151976,-122.25095326385497)\\
</item><item>
Alpha Phi Sorority\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86926374344789,-122.25080609321594)	(37.86899078634905,-122.2502022453308)\\
</item><item>
Chi Psi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.868874145966835,-122.25205063819885)	(37.86857578084269,-122.25143606147765)\\
</item><item>
Pi Beta Phi Sorority\\
\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86856077258499,-122.25195407867432)	(37.86831322549457,-122.25137168846129)\\
</item><item>
Phi Kappa Tau Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86828974588268,-122.25185751914978)	(37.86810995634968,-122.25131804428099)\\
</item><item>
Phi Gamma Delta Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86810341444657,-122.25179314613342)	(37.86787280769221,-122.25125367126464)\\
</item><item>
Alpha Chi Omega Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.868848737363905,-122.2507095336914)	(37.868609659241415,-122.25013787231444)\\
</item><item>
Alpha Tau Omega Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.868586181287235,-122.25067734718323)	(37.8683216949535,-122.25008422813414)\\
</item><item>
Alpha Omicron Pi Sorority\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86896731076927,-122.2500228881836)	(37.86858424990357,-122.24956924400328)\\
</item><item>
Zeta Psi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86944160248264,-122.2534453868866)	(37.869075481081,-122.25303465805052)\\
</item><item>
Sigma Alpha Epsilon Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.869382316185416,-122.25383162498474)	(37.86904160280448,-122.25342089614867)\\
</item><item>
Sigma Nu Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.8693230298405,-122.25415349006653)	(37.86898231650728,-122.25377494773863)\\
</item><item>
Kappa Alpha Theta Sorority\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86881485921303,-122.25369215011597)	(37.86851649417066,-122.2531741329193)\\
</item><item>
Phi Kappa Psi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.867840855714086,-122.25129961967468)	(37.867525552963244,-122.25086743316649)\\
</item><item>
Delta Upsilon Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.8672903263021,-122.25062370300293)	(37.866780219328405,-122.25010568580626)\\
</item><item>
Tau House\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.867747689487345,-122.25166440010071)	(37.867347689487346,-122.25126440010071)\\
</item><item>
Pi Kappa Phi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86792555218162,-122.25035548210144)	(37.86760177933296,-122.24995548210143)\\
</item><item>
Alpha Delta Pi Sorority\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86765452314282,-122.2523295879364)	(37.86723758384078,-122.25196177444457)\\
</item><item>
Gamma Phi Beta Sorority\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.867603705087035,-122.25270509719849)	(37.86718676568137,-122.25232655487059)\\
</item><item>
Beta Theta Pi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86755288699624,-122.25311279296875)	(37.867152886996244,-122.25271279296875)\\
</item><item>
Phi Delta Delta Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.867519008249566,-122.25342392921448)	(37.86711900824957,-122.25302392921448)\\
</item><item>
Alpha Delta Phi Sorority\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.867468190100354,-122.2502052783966)	(37.867068190100355,-122.24980527839661)\\
</item><item>
Tau Kappa Epsilon Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86806953595301,-122.25319862365723)	(37.86765259670042,-122.25289518318175)\\
</item><item>
Pi Lambda Phi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86810341444657,-122.25287675857544)	(37.867703414630476,-122.25260550460814)\\
</item><item>
Delta Chi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86804412707261,-122.25350975990295)	(37.867635657397905,-122.25319559059142)\\
</item><item>
Delta Gamma Sorority\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86747665979434,-122.25393891334534)	(37.867119008663366,-122.25358182868956)\\
</item><item>
Alpha Delta Chi Christian Sorority\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.865757291958076,-122.25245833396912)	(37.86540811179295,-122.25203687629698)\\
</item><item>
Alpha Sigma Phi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.866273953504525,-122.25209355354309)	(37.865873953504526,-122.25169355354309)\\
</item><item>
Alpha Epsilon Pi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86668897409031,-122.25221157073975)	(37.86634826287646,-122.25181157073973)\\
</item><item>
Kappa Alpha Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.8669261276613,-122.25157856941223)	(37.86664470480425,-122.25108200988768)\\
</item><item>
Theta Chi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86630783282362,-122.25129961967468)	(37.86595018218049,-122.25089961967467)\\
</item><item>
Chi Omega Sorority\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.8672479777154,-122.25139617919922)	(37.86697502427599,-122.25085670433043)\\
</item><item>
Theta Xi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.86867934645378,-122.25537657737732)	(37.8683725120083,-122.25500876388548)\\
</item><item>
Theta Delta Chi Fraternity\\
life\\
Built 0\\
\\
\\
(37.868764041957526,-122.254958152771)	(37.86842332907406,-122.25454742393492)\\
</item></string-array></resources>